<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-14T19:11:20+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Next Book</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/11/next-book.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Next Book" /><published>2024-05-11T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-11T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/05/11/next-book</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/11/next-book.html"><![CDATA[<p>Next book to read: Gödel, Escher, Bach</p>

<p>By exploring common themes in the lives and works of logician Kurt Gödel, artist M. C. Escher, and composer Johann Sebastian Bach, the book expounds concepts fundamental to mathematics, symmetry, and intelligence. Through short stories, illustrations, and analysis, the book discusses how systems can acquire meaningful context despite being made of “meaningless” elements. It also discusses self-reference and formal rules, isomorphism, what it means to communicate, how knowledge can be represented and stored, the methods and limitations of symbolic representation, and even the fundamental notion of “meaning” itself.</p>

<p>In response to confusion over the book’s theme, Hofstadter emphasized that Gödel, Escher, Bach is not about the relationships of mathematics, art, and music—but rather about how cognition emerges from hidden neurological mechanisms. One point in the book presents an analogy about how individual neurons in the brain coordinate to create a unified sense of a coherent mind by comparing it to the social organization displayed in a colony of ants.</p>

<p>Gödel, Escher, Bach won the Pulitzer Prize for general non-fiction and the National Book Award for Science Hardcover. Despite the success of the book, Hofstadter felt that audiences did not adequately grasp what he felt was the main idea of the book: strange loops. In an attempt to remedy this, he published I Am a Strange Loop in 2007.</p>]]></content><author><name>gustav</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Next book to read: Gödel, Escher, Bach]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Favorite Book</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/10/favorite-book.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Favorite Book" /><published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-05-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2024/05/10/favorite-book</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2024/05/10/favorite-book.html"><![CDATA[<p>The Pragmatic Programmer</p>

<p>The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master is a book about computer programming and software engineering, written by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas and published in October 1999. It is used as a textbook in related university courses.</p>]]></content><author><name>gustav</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pragmatic Programmer]]></summary></entry></feed>